Wyatt Towne

wymtowne@gmail.com / 989-397-5957 / 5038 Reinhardt Ln, Bay City, Michigan

Summary

I have several years of professional industry experience under my belt, working in a variety of team environments and technology stacks. I have a passion for exploring new things and seeking to push the bounds of innovation. For a more in depth look at some of my projects, both for my job and personal, please refer to my digital portfolio: https://wyatttowne.com/

Experience

Software Developer

Dow • Auburn, MI 01/2022 - Present

- · Apart of an agile development team managing and developing a large enterprise application hosted in Azure
- Primarily worked in the Angular frameowork, C# .Net framework, SQL, and many Azure cloud service offerings such as Azure Functions, Service Bus, Key Store, and PIM.
- Participated in Daily Standups, sprint end retrospectives, and code reviews

Software Developer

Dow • Auburn, MI 06/2020 - 01/2022

- Designed and developed webapps for various functions and businesses in the UI5 framework, deployed to SAP Cloud Platform.
- Designed and developed Powerapps and Power Automate flows to automate processes and teams across the company.
- Managed a suite of mobile apps on both the Apple App Store and Android Play Store, performing certificate resigns, wrapping internal enterprise apps for Intune distribution, troubleshooting user reported issues.
- Helped integrate Dynatrace monitoring platform into team's suite of webapps to increase visibility of reported issues/bugs and unexpected outages.

Software Developer Co-op

Dow • Midland, MI 08/2017 - 05/2020

- Developed desktop applications in VB.net for chemists and chemical engineers, primarily for data processing.
- Ensured minimal downtown of teams lab computers by pushing monthly updates and security patches, and monitoring internal network for outages.
- Helped install and deploy Acronis backup software across teams computer infrastructure to persist data in the unexpected event of a failure or outage.

Operations Intern

Consumers Energy • Saginaw, MI 06/2017 - 08/2017

- Worked directly under a regional manager to deploy lean business solutions across the company.
- Decreased preparation time for line workers by helping develop processes to have their tools and materials prestaged before ariving on site.

Personal Projects

Digital Portfolio: https://wyatttowne.com/

Education

Computer Science

Saginaw Valley State University • Saginaw, MI 05/2020

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Honors: summa cum laude (highest distinction)

GPA: 3.82

ACM Person of the year award

- For outstanding involvement in ACM activities and volunteer opportunities.

Member:

- · Associated for Computing Machinery
- · Robotics Club
- International Collegiate Programming Competition University Team

References

Heather McPhee, Solution Manager

Dow

5300 11 Mile Rd.

Auburn, MI 48611

(989) 992-2288

Joshua Durham, Software Engineer

Dow

627 Washington St.

Midland, MI 48640

(989) 245-3625

Dave Myers, IT Technician

Dow

627 Washington St.

Midland, MI 48640

(231) 392-3242

James Slieff, Executive Director Electric Operations

Consumers Energy

2400 Weiss St.

Saginaw, MI 48602

(989) 450-4361

Aos Mulahuwaish, Professor of Computer Science

Saginaw Valley State University

7400 Bay Rd, Science East 174

University Center, MI 48710

Phone: 989-964-4346